

KATRI ELIANDER

UX DESIGNER

BRIEFLY ABOUT ME

I am a UX Designer with a background in online marketing. My UX Design skills combined with my experience in marketing provide me with a strategic problem-solving mindset and a holistic understanding for designing solutions that will increase both user experience and business value.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Fluency in Finnish, Swedish, English

Intermediate skills in German and Spanish

TOOLS

Adobe XD, Balsamiq, Google Analytics

InVision and Sketch (basics but learning)

CONTACT INFORMATION

e-mail: katrieliander@gmail.com phone: +358442956136 Berlin, Germany

<u>Linkedin</u>

<u>Portfolio</u>

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer (volunteer, part-time)

slavefreetrade (05/2020-)

slavefreetrade is a NGO with a mission to build a world where all goods are made without harming anyone. I will be helping out on different UX projects, for instance an app that will collect human rights data throughout supply chains.

SEO Manager

Internetstores GmbH, Berlin (07/2017-12/2019)

- Responsibility for both on-page and off-page SEO for the company's two Finnish web shops
- Planning and implementation of content marketing and link building strategies for increasing brand awareness, visibility and drive traffic

E-Commerce SEO Consultant

Arvo Partners (e-commerce consultancy), Helsinki (09/2015-06/2017)

- -Responsibility for planning and implementing SEO strategies for small to large sized e-commerce businesses in various industries
- Monitoring, analyzing and reporting on clients' organic visibility, traffic and sales

PR Account Coordinator

JB Cumberland PR, New York (08/2014 - 02/2015)

- Strategic and operational PR for the agency's lifestyle and design brands
- Development and implementation of PR programs and strategies for clients, outreach to major media outlets and bloggers, management of clients' social media platforms

EDUCATION

Certified UX Designer

CareerFoundry, Berlin (2019-2020)

A 8-month long online program that covers all areas of user centered design. Throughout the course I worked on a project (iOS app) and was mentored by an industry expert with several years of experience in the field.

Master of Economics & Business Administration

Hanken School of Economics, Helsinki (2012-2015)

Major: Marketing (GPA: 90)